Tareq Dabaan

Kuwait, Salmiya| (+965) 97808678 call | (+963) 992327821 WhatsApp tareqdab2000@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

About me

Motivated Software Engineer full of potential, ready to take chances and determined to succeed, specializing in Backend development, Django and Django Rest Framework for server-side logic. Proficient in foundational programming principles with a drive to craft high-performing web applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Remostart, Software Engineer – Django backend developer (Trainee)

June. 2023 - Jan. 2024

Remote

- Developing backend systems using Python Django
- Building REST APIs
- · Designing database
- Building UML diagrams
- Integrating and dealing with frontend developers

Remostart, Med_Sal project - Backend developer

Aug. 2023 - Dec. 2023

Remote

A web/mobile platform connecting patients with healthcare providers (doctors, pharmacies) in UAE.

- Optimized backend architecture and API performance for seamless user experience
- Designed and implemented a secure, scalable PostgreSQL database and robust RESTful APIs using Python Django/DRF.
- Technologies used: Python Django, DRF, PostgreSQL, GeoDjango, Postman, Git and docker
- Contributed to a team of 4 developers in building the system
- · Github link, API docs

AmaratLines Mar. 2024

Kuwait City, Kuwait

A website for a construction company based in Kuwait. The project is a static website for the company.

Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, JS and Godaddy for hosting

Website Link: https://amaratlines.com/

Syrian Adventurer Aug. 2024

Lattakia, Syria

A system for the adventurer association for mountains activities, which contains a dashboard for the admin with AI algorithms to recommend best activities the admin can create, a user-friendly interface for users to browse and book activities.

Technologies Used: Django, TOPSIS algorithm, PostgreSQL, Postgis, Reactjs

- · Optimized backend architecture and API performance for seamless user experience
- Designed and implemented a secure, scalable PostgreSQL database and robust RESTful APIs using Python Django/DRF.
- Implemented TOPSIS algorithm for multicriteria decision making to help admins take decisions about activity data (location, date, price...etc)
- The admin have full visualization about all the system's data such as users, past activities, most loved activities ... etc
- Contributed to a team of 3 developers in building the system

EDUCATION

AI-Baath University – Bachelor Information Technology Engineering Department of Software Engineering and Information Systems

Sep 2019 - Aug 2024

SKILLS

- Python (Django, Django Rest Framework, Flask)
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- SQL (MySQL, PostgreSQL).

- MVC, REST, microservices
- JSON, XML.
- Git
- API Testing (Postman, Swagger)
- Design patterns, OOP, Algorithms.
- Agile methodologies, JIRA, Scrum, Docker, GIT, SDLC.
- Machine learning basics using Python libraries.

Languages

- English Fluent
- Arabic Native

Certificates